U.S. National Mediation Board Records Regarding General Managers Association of New York and the International Longshoremen's Association, Lighter Captains Union, Local 996 5089
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. National Mediation Board Records Regarding General Managers Association of New York and the International Longshoremen's Association, Lighter Captains Union, Local 996
1956-1957
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. National Mediatoin Board
General Managers Association of New York
International Longshoremen's Association (ILA), Lighter Captains Union
5089
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Photographs, proceedings, transcripts.
United States. National Mediation Board. Arbitration case no. 225: Labor Committee of the General Managers' Association of New York, representing New York Harbor Railroads vs. the Lighter Captains' Union, International Longshoremen's Association: proceedings and exhibits, 1957.
3336290
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 04, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 31, 2016
Biographical / Historical
In April of 1957, a labor dispute arose between the Lighter Captains Union, Local 996, International Longshoremen's Association, and the eight railroads that operated New fork City's harbor barges and tugboats, represented by the Labor Committee of the General Managers' Association of New York. Both parties agreed to take their dispute to the National Mediation Board.
The Union demanded an immediate increase of 42 1/2 cents per hour in basic rates, an additional 20 cents per hour for overtime work, and a minimum wage of $25 per day for workers on refrigerator boats or those equipped with power hoists. The railroads did not offer any increase. After two weeks of hearings, the Board recommended a three fear collective agreement with a wage increase of 24 cents per hour.
Scope and Contents
Consist of transcript of proceedings (734 pp.) and nineteen exhibits submitted to the Board by the Lighter Captains' Union and by the Labor Committee. The exhibits give a detailed description of the occupation and of the wage structure of the railroad industry. Included are studies of domestic and export lighterage freight handled; classes, numbers, and representation of railroad marine workers; and lighterage and terminal regulations in New York Harbor, among other exhibits.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5082: U.S. National Mediation Board Transcript of Hearings Regarding the BRAC 5083: U.S. National Mediation Board Transcripts Regarding United Air Lines and Air Line Pilots Association 5085: U.S. National Mediation Board Transcripts Regarding American Air Lines and Transport Workers Union of America 5086: U.S. National Mediation Board Transcripts Regarding New York Central Railroad Company and BRAC 5087: U.S. National Mediation Board Records Regarding Eastern, Western, and Southeastern Carriers' Conference Committee and the Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers 5088: U.S. National Mediation Board Records Regarding Eastern, Western, and Southeastern Carriers' Conference Committee and the Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers 5089: U.S. National Mediation Board Records Regarding General Managers Association of New York and the International Longshoremen's Association, Lighter Captains Union, Local 996 5090: U.S. National Mediation Board Records Regarding Chicago and Northwestern Railway Company et al. and the Order of Railroad Telegraphers 5579: National Mediation Board Emergency Board 180, Train Crew Consists 5748 OHM: National Mediation Board Airline Industry Arbitration Oral History Interviews 5806: U.S. National Mediation Board Agreements
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Cases; Stevedores; Arbitration, Industrial -- Merchant marine -- United States; Arbitration, Industrial -- Railroads -- United States; New York Harbor (N.Y. and N.J.); Railroad marine workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Wages -- Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; General Managers' Association of New York; Lighter Captains' Union; United States. National Mediation Board; International Longshoremen's Association; International Longshoremen's Association. Local 966 (New York, N.Y.)
3336290
- Exhibits. (Box 1)
  - The Parties and Issues Before the Board, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Classes and Numbers of All Railroad Employees, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Classes, Numbers, and Representation of Railroad Marine Employees., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report of National Mediation Board Including the Report of the National Railroad Adjustment Board., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Wage Statistics, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Marine Equipment Used By New York Harbor Roads, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Scope and Contents
    As of June 1, 1957
  - Net Tons of Domestic and Export Lighterage Freight Handled by Railroads Servicing the Port of New York, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Transcript, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Lighterage and Terminal Regulations in New York Harbor and Vicinity, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Marine Equipment, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Work Studies, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Occupational Wage Survey, New York, New York, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    April, 1956
  - Wage Diversity, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Illustrations of Uniform Wage Change for Unions Within an Industry or Company, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Diverse Wage Patterns Within a Union, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Pattern Settlements in the Railroad Industry, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Report to the President by the Emergency Board, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Emergency Board Appointed by Executive Order 10693, December 22, 1956, President to Section 10 of the Railway Labor Act, as amended, to investigate and report on a dispute between the Akron and Barlarton Railroad Company and the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen.
  - Report to the President by the Emergency Board, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Emergency Board Appointed by Executive Order 10693, December 22, 1956, President to Section 10 of the Railway Labor Act, as amended, to investigate a dispute between the Railway Express Agency, Incorporated, and the International Brotherhood of Teamsters.
  - Participation of International Longshoremen's Association with other Railroad Nonoperating Employees for Purposes of Collective Bargaining., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Pattern Settlements in the Railroad Industry - National Agreements, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)